史蒂文听故事
本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
哇  爸爸  赞
Whoo! Go, Dad!
■
时间轴： 树叶
我跟你说什么来着  虽然岁月不饶人
See? What'd I tell you? I may be losing my hair
■
翻译： Chim
但我光彩依旧
but the magic's still there. Hmm?
■
校订： 树叶
照片里你旁边这个人是谁
Who's with you in this old picture?
-那是我的朋友马蒂  -你从没跟我提起过他
- That's my pal Marty. - You've never told me about him.
■
后期： 树叶  小黑
是啊  他只是一个旧时的老友而已
Yeah, he's just an old amigo from way back when.
-我早就不在乎他了  -他到底是谁
- He's dead to me. - Who was he?
他是我的经纪人  就在我刚遇见你妈妈的那会儿
He was my manager back when I first met your mom.
我早就讲过那段故事了  是吧
I've told you that whole story, haven't I?
但没讲过带马蒂的版本
Not the version with Marty.
好吧  故事时间到
Geesh. Then it's story time.
找个舒服的位置坐好
Sit back. Get comfy.
-我可没说躺下啊  -史蒂文要听故事
- I didn't mean that comfy. - Story for Steven!
好吧好吧  这是一关于我
Okay, okay. This is the tale of how your
和你妈妈相遇的故事  不过多了个马蒂
father met your mother. Now including Marty.
有人说我没有目标
Some say I have no direction
说我容易分心
that I'm a light-speed distraction
但那只不过是第一印象
but that's a knee-jerk reaction
这仍然是最后的边界
still this is the final frontier
一切都显得如此清晰明了
everything is so clear
我的命运由我来掌握
to my destiny I steer
这是我所了解的星际生活
this life in the stars is all I've ever known
我的家是那浩瀚无尽的星辰宇宙
stars and stardust and infinite space is my only home
但是在我登上舞台的瞬间
but the moment that I hit the stage
宇宙先生
成千上万人呼喊我的名字
thousands of voices are calling my name
在我的内心深处  我明白这一切都值得
and I know in my heart it's been worth it all of the while
当我的专辑从货架上售罄
and as my albums fly off of the shelves
亲手送出我的签名照
handing out autographed pics of myself
这样的生活虽来之不易  但绝对是个极好的经历
this life I chose isn't easy but sure is one heck of a ride
在我登上舞台的瞬间
at the moment that I hit the stage
听到宇宙呼喊我的名字
I hear the universe calling my name
我知道在内心深处
and I know deep down in my heart
我无所畏惧
I have nothing to fear
当太阳风吹动我的长发
and as the solar wind blows through my hair
我明白我还有很多东西可以分享
knowing I have so much more left to share
流浪的灵魂在寒冷的空气中
a wandering spirit who's tearing its way
撕开一条道路
through the cold atmosphere
我如彗星一般飞行
I fly like a comet
如彗星一般翱翔
soar like a comet
如彗星一般坠毁
crash like a comet
我只是一颗彗星
I'm just a comet
感谢各位的到来  我是宇宙先生
Thanks for coming, everybody. I'm Mr. Universe.
如果你喜欢我的表演
If you liked what you just heard
可以我们的周边售卖区  我的经纪人
go check out our merch table. My manager,
马蒂  将会为你送上我的CD和T恤
Marty, can hook you up with CDs and T-shirts.
等等  他不在那  我想得我亲自过去了
Oh, wait. He's not there. I guess I'm going over there now.
-开往宇宙的太空列车  -没错
- "Space train to the cosmos." - Yeah!
手握单程车票  我早已准备出发
One-way ticket and I'm ready to ri-i-de
那你打算怎么回来
Oh. But how will you get back?
-回来  -回到地球
- Back? - Back to Earth?
-我不会回来了  -这太糟糕了
- I'm never coming back. - Ugh, that's awful!
这可是你的家呀
This is your home.
你想要这张CD吗  拿去吧
You want that? You can have it!
还附赠一件免费T恤
Oh, and it comes with a free T-shirt!
不过你可能需要一件更大的
You'll probably need a bigger one.
车里有XXL号的  我去给你拿
I've got an extra extra-large in my van. Stay right there!
星空小子  来见见维达莉亚
Starchild! Meet Vidalia.
车不错  生活很滋润嘛
Nice van. Really living the high life.
-嗯  演出如何  -还不错
- So, how was the show? - It was great!
来了一位观众
One person showed up!
对了  我得送给她这件T恤
Oh! I have to give her this free T... shirt.
格雷格  你不能随随便便把东西送人
Greg! You can't give stuff away for free!
里面有我75%的提成呢
What about my 75%?
这样我一分钱也拿不到
75% of nothing is nothing!
你就那么一文不值吗
Are you worth nothing?
-当然不是  -这才对啊
- No. - That's right!
我要让我们俩都发家致富
I'm gonna make us both rich!
而且在这些大傻瓜心中
And as far as these saltwater saps know
我们已经是有钱人了
we already are!
所以在出发之前  就尽情狂欢吧
So let's live it up before we hit the road all right?
下一站是帝国市
Next stop ... Empire City!
那什么  我晚点再过去
You know... I'll catch up with you.
-也许她在那里面  -谁
- Maybe she's over there? - Whooo?
一个留着茂盛粉红色头发的
Oh, just some giant mysterious lady
高大的神秘女子
with enormous pink hair.
你在附近没见过这样的人吧
You haven't seen anyone like that around, have you?
当然见过了  伙计
Sure have, pal.
-哪  哪里  -这个嘛
- Wh-Where? - Well, uh...
如果我再跟你多说下去  我就必须得把你杀了
if I told you any more, I'd have to kill you!!
等等  等一下
Hey! Wait! Hold on a sec!
这个长头发的人类
This long-haired human
刚刚在围栏边和我说话
was talking to me over by the fence.
-它对你讲话了吗  -他问我关于罗丝的事
- It spoke to you? - He was asking about Rose.
看  他就在那
Look! There he is!
紫晶  等等
Amethyst! Wait!
是你
It's you!
我从来没见过有人到这来
I've never seen this one around here before.
-我喜欢你的发型  -紫晶  离他远点
- Oh, I really like your hair. - Amethyst, leave him be!
你还不知道他什么来路
You don't know where he's been!
我为她的行为道歉  对你道歉
I'm very sorry about this, uh, you?
天呐  紫晶
Oh, Amethyst.
-你带来一个人类  -是他尾随我过来的
- You're with a human. - He followed me over the fence.
我们现在该怎么办
What should we do?
-快说你有什么目的  -我想找一个人
- State your purpose. - Uh, I was kind of looking
一位神秘的粉色女士  非常高大
for the mysterious pink lady, kind of really tall,
有着巨大浓密的卷发
lots of big, curly hair.
你看吧  他说的就是罗…
See? He's talking about Ro...
我不知道要怎样才能让他离开
I don't know how to make him go away
那就让我直接把他丢出围栏好了
I'll just throw him back over the fence
这方法不错  人类就应该
Excellent idea. Humans should stay on
遵守围墙上的警示  不要踏进这里来
the other side of the fence like the sign says.
-求求你  别用扔的  -等等
- Please! No throwing! - Wait!
-宇宙先生  -是你
- Mr. Universe? - It's you.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
-你认识这个人类吗  -他刚刚在沙滩上
- You know this human?! - He was playing a concert
举办了演唱会  我被他的歌声深深吸引了
on the beach, and... I couldn't help myself.
谁都无法拒绝宇宙的魅力
No one could ignore the Universe.
对了  我给你带来了这件免费T恤
Oh! I brought you this! It's the free T-shirt that
-是你的免费CD附赠的  -谢谢
- came with your free CD! - Why, thank you!
他的宣传主题是太空哦
His gimmick is space!
那唱首歌吧  大音乐家
Hey, play something, music man!
最好能打动我
Better make it good.
正好  我在写一首超赞的新歌
Aw, man. I'm working on this awesome new set.
一定能在下一场演唱会大放光彩
It's gonna kill at my next show.
等等  下一场
"Next show"?
噢不  现在几点了
Aw, geez. What time is it?
大概是晚点
Night... time?
好吧  马蒂估计在找我
Yeah, Marty's probably looking for me.
我们该出发去下一个城市了
We're supposed to hit the road.
有一场在繁华城市的盛大演出
It's a big show in a big city,
我可不是平白无故从社区大学辍学的
and I didn't drop out of community college for nothing!
-什么  -你可得快点了
- What? - Well, you better hurry.
你一定不想错过开往宇宙的太空列车
You don't want to miss your space train to the cosmos.
-好  -再见了
- Okay! - I’ll see you later!
希望星星会列成桥梁  使我们再次见到对方
Uh, I hope the stars will align for us to meet again!
一定会的
I'm sure they will!
再见了音乐家
Bye, music man!
我也会唱歌啊
I can sing.
怎么了
What?
天哪格雷格  你错过了狂欢
Man, Greg, you really missed out.
维达莉亚的朋友们非常疯狂
Vidalia's friends were wild and crazy.
-这个小镇算是没白来  -我也遇到了几位疯狂的女士
- Glad that town wasn't a total waste. - I met some wild ladies, too.
她们能易形  还能从光束中现身
They change shape and appear out of beams of light.
这种故事留到帝国市再说吧
Save the poetry for Empire City,
星空小子  明天对于我们将会是重要的一天
starchild. We've got a big day ahead of us tomorrow.
我是认真的  马蒂
I'm serious, Marty.
-刚才真的发生了不寻常的事  -你是不是傻
- Something's going on back there. - Are you nuts?
等你看到我们的未来 充满荣誉和名利
Just wait till you see what's ahead of us. It's fame!
有什么东西卡在你的磁带槽里了
Hey, what's jammed in your tape deck?
你在里面放了硬币吗  怪咖
You been putting pennies in here,you weirdo?
给我唱首歌吧  星空小子
Play something for me, Starchild.
你相信命运吗
Do you believe in destiny?
闭上双眼  把一切放心交给我
close your eyes and leave the rest to me
呼噜  你这样唱人们会睡着
Snore! You're gonna put people to sleep with that!
这样的烂歌你是怎么想到的
Where's this schlock coming from?
我只是情不自禁的想到演出上的那位女子
I-I just can't stop thinking about that woman at the show.
说来听听  她有多高
Oh, here we go. How big was she?
大概两米四  有茂盛的头发
8 feet tall... massive hair.
格雷格 这就是你的问题了
See, Greg, this is your problem.
你可以拥有许多小巧的女人  却非要喜欢一个高大的
You want one huge woman when you can have multiple smaller ones.
-马蒂  女人也是人啊  -你只要乖乖听我的
- Marty, women are people. - Just follow my lead.
我会让你得到你想要的一切
I'm gonna get you everything you want.
-如果我想回到那个小镇呢  -什么
- What if I want to go back? - What?!
如果我想回去跟她在一起呢
What if I want to go back and be with her?!
没人会在乎你想要什么  格雷格
No one cares about your feelings, Greg!
她们让你忽视了真正重要的事
They're making you lose sight of what's really important!
看着点路
Watch the road!
为什么总要由你来决定什么更重要
Why do you always decide what's important?
因为我是经纪人  你只是个脑子不清醒的傻小孩
Because I'm your manager, and you're just some spaced-out kid!
我要带你去帝国市  你要去演出
I'm taking you to the city, and you're gonna play
而且你会喜欢那里
and you're gonna like it.
说不定还能给我赚点小钱
Maybe you'll even make me some money for once.
从我的车里滚出去
Get out of my van.
快坐下  格雷格
Sit down, Greg.
我说了  从我的车里滚出去
I said, get out of my van!
你这是干什么
Ooh! What are you doing?!
你在犯一个大错误
You're making a huge mistake!
嘿  你在里面吗
Hey! Are you in there?
我可以给你唱歌了  我改编了那首超棒的歌
I can play for you now! I even revamped my awesome set!
这首歌为你而唱  神秘女郎
This one's for you, mystery woman!
你相信命运吗
Do you believe in destiny?
闭上双眼  把一切放心交给我
close your eyes and leave the rest to me
你相信幻想吗
do you believe in fantasy?
当幻想变成现实  我必须去相信
I have to when it's right in front of me
你在这做什么呢
what are you doing here?
在这真实的世界里
in the real world
你在这做什么呢
what are you doing here?
离我如此近  使我伸手就能触碰到你
so close I could touch you
你在这做什么呢
what are you doing here?
你又在对我做什么
and what are you doing to me-e-e?
你穿着  那件T恤呀
Oh! You're wearing the... shirt.
-你走吧  拜托了  -对不起
- Please go away. - I-I'm sorry.
我是不是…
Did I...?
你非常可爱  我也很想和你在一起
You're awfully cute. And I really want to play with you.
但是你的人生短暂  也还有梦想
But your life is short, and you have dreams.
我不能让你放弃你想要的一切
I won't let you give up on everything you want.
这就是个问题了
Well, that's gonna be a problem.
-什么  -你就是我想要的一切
- Huh? - You're everything I want!
-你笑什么呢  -你爱她
- What are you smiling about? - You loved her!
你给我过来
Come here, you!
天哪
Oh, man.
-马蒂真的是个很糟糕的人  -是啊
- Marty was the worst! - Oh, yeah.
他是很糟糕  但我也欠了他很多
He was awful! But I guess I owe him a lot.
是他让我选择留在这里
He made it easy for me to stay.
我很高兴你这样做了
I'm glad you did.
我也是
Yeah, me too.